three what is the iup pack name for the
following compound we have another one
here we have a cyclohexane so the way
that we name cyclohexanes is a little
bit different from linear molecules what
we need to do is we need to find the
lowest set of locant possible so we have
three substituents and we need to number
the ring so as to give them the lowest
set of locant possible one could be any
of these carbons and then we go either
clockwise or counterclockwise but it
happens to be the case that this is the
lowest set of locant that we can get is
if we do 1 2 4 so if we started with the
ethyl we could get 134 if we started
with the bromo we could get 125 right
none of these are the lowest possible
the one that I've drawn right here
that's the lowest set of loans possible
we have to do it that way because these
alkal and hallogen substituents are all
of equal priority so we just go 1 2 3 4
5 6 like that